[Music]
good evening and welcome to the free
assange vigil number
46.1 we are
46 weeks straight into this series uh my
name is steve boykinen i am joined by my
co-host andrew smith and kendra
christian
uh today marks 3
451 days since the illegal and arbitrary
detention of julian assange began
404 days since he was trafficked out of
the ecuador and nbc after being stolen
from a 4.2 billion dollar imf loan to
ecuador
111 days until the second round of
extradition hearings begin in london and
our protests begin in dc
uh
1081 days of incarceration throughout
reality winner and on the plus side uh
67 days of freedom for chelsea manning
following the decade-long wikileaks
grand jury dismissal uh we are joined
tonight by the convo couches fiorella
isabel
by the uh ron paul institutes norman
singleton and i believe eventually john
kiriakou will be on as well
um guys we are uh
we are organizing for dc
as we speak and uh as such
we are trying to get our sorry behinds
there um we do have a gofundme up we're
gonna post the link a few times
throughout the video tonight feel free
to uh uh share the link if you can't
donate if you can donate please do that
um the the uh
trial is gonna last about three weeks we
are trying to make sure that at least
some of us are there for all three of
those weeks um so please if you can
donate if you can't share the link um
let's go ahead and
and start off the round uh of interviews
though um
how's goofy how you doing it's good to
see you
it's going well what's going well you
know quarantining doing as many shows as
possible
um still trying to get as much
information out there as possible taking
care of this advantage of this time to
actually
be putting out as much content and be uh
diving deep into
what's left of the electoral process in
this country which is a sad sad um
state of affairs right now
um given that what is work
well that's exactly it um
you know there's a lot of confused
people left people that need
guidance um but i think it's actually an
opportunity to take things outside of
electoral politics um and actually go in
that direction and stop relying on
politicians to be this whole
people that change anything
right like there's a lot of movements
that we could be a part of
i couldn't agree with that more i've
been screaming at people since the mid
90s when i could vote for the first time
that
putting your uh putting your faith in in
politicians is
the last possible thing you would want
to do and that voting is the laziest and
least effective political action anyone
can make
uh
having said that
um
i guess there there's uh there's
probably still down but like they
haven't canceled elections entirely yet
they're going to try according to greg
palace up to 20 of the vote can be
tampered with by mail-in ballot which i
guess is a little bit better than going
and voting on an electronic machine
yeah i'm not i'm not entirely sure about
that i don't know
um
uh we are we are actually john kariaki
who's in the house now too john how you
doing hey folks how are you steve doing
well it's good to see you again sir
pleasure um
and i'm gonna pitch this one to uh i'm
gonna pitch this one to norm first and
then you guys can hop in
um
at
what point
do people uh
do people stop paying attention to
electoral politics as the sole vehicle
through which change can happen
and that one's for you norm but if he
doesn't unmute then somebody else can
field it
sorry about that i'm putting my dog away
okay actually um
and uh
funny because dogs
sometimes politicians you have to treat
them like like you would treat a
a dog or a toddler which is discipline
and constant um
watching them and not uh
them get away with anything
and i think that the question about
electoral politics
i see the point that people say it's a
dead end
i would say that the problem
is not so much that it's a dead end or
that people put too much faith in
politicians
um i would actually say that you
shouldn't put any faith in politicians
uh as a christian i actually have a
messiah a savior named jesus christ and
i really prefer him to donald trump or
joe biden
um
but
you
the the the
thing that
people fail to do
in political movements enough of is
holding politicians accountable
and forgetting that the real work begins
the day after election because you
really need to be
pressuring constantly the politicians to
make sure they keep their promises to
make sure they don't portray you to make
sure they don't sell you out to the
special interest and the party
leadership
and not to step on anybody's toes here
but from what i've been seeing and
reading and hearing lately
from a few
progressive sources
particularly jimmy dore
is that correct pronunciation
in
is that
and some others is that
the left is actually doing a fairly bad
job of that
much worse than the right did
i think the freedom caucus did a much
better job of trying to hold boehner and
ryan accountable
and standing up to them than the
progressive caucus is doing with nancy
pelosi
i don't i personally don't think the
progressive caucus is incentivized to
hold to any sort of progressive ideals
there the there's no accountability
because they're either going to get
primaried from within the democratic
party or they're going to get primaried
by somebody else who's going to go to
washington and run up against the wall
that is nancy pelosi passing 82 to 88 of
donald trump's agenda that's chuck
schumer voting to fast track what now uh
a total of a total of 198 judges but
fast tracking 37 of them they're running
into a machine that incentivizes them to
participate and to ignore the electorate
and and fees got the fees got the pulse
on this because that's what her show
covers 99 you know well
that's what the organization that i i
run and i just want to correct briefly
that my introduction is i'm
i'm uh with campaign for liberty which
is dr ron paul's 501 c 4 grassroots
activism and education group uh we are
separate from the ron paul institute
which is a 501 c 3 educational
foundation that focuses on foreign
policy and civil liberties although i'm
a big fan
and good friend of daniel mcadams and a
fan of everything that the institute
does
but i think that what we do at campaign
for liberty is we try to mobilize people
to call email
and write their representatives on
legislation i know people can be cynical
and say well what good does one phone
call do
well one phone call doesn't do actually
doesn't do any good but multiply but
multiply one by 100 phone calls and then
you're you're you are actually going to
make an impact uh there's strength in
numbers there is strength and
accountability and there is strength in
backbone and a lot of there's a lot of
guys so when i worked for dr paul for 15
years on capitol hill from 1997 to 2012
11 of those is this legislative director
which is the top policy job at a
congressional office and i can tell you
from that we did see
a change in how
politicians were willing members of
congress were willing to stand up and
stand with dr paul on issues like the
fed and um
and even um opposing the patriot act and
foreign interventionism and that wasn't
because all of a sudden they had a come
to jesus moment
and realized that ron was right it was
because they saw that there was a
constituency out there for these ideas
that was mobilized enthusiastic and was
actually coming to their town hall
meetings
calling their office writing their
offices emailing their offices and
demanding that they stand with ron
you know we just had a
vote on provisions
of the patriot act being reauthorized i
believe permanently
um
how about gophy
um well it went really bad i mean
there's several things there's the uh
hr 666
that allows uh
that it's just
less more price uh violation of privacy
rights against people then there's the
uh
resolution that was just voted down it
was an amendment to protect the fbi from
going after
your browser history and uh 10 10
senators didn't show up for that but it
was only in the senate the house hasn't
voted on it yet and one of those
senators was senator bernie sanders he
hasn't necessarily been
the staunchest advocate of civil
liberties i feel like that is one of his
uh weak points
from a pers from my perspective
but
it was important that he was there and
he didn't show up and that als that
sparked a lot of criticism
because if he is to be the leader even
still right now of the progressive
movement he should be protecting our
civil liberties and i i think that's a
very
general um assertion what is civil
liberties i mean a lot of people in on
the left and i consider myself to be
part of the left do not even care or
realize how important
their civil liberties are they see that
as a libertarian construct and they look
at it with disdain and i think that is
because some of the uh you know the
republican more conservative side of the
libertarian movement has kind of been
against social safety nets but i think
there is a coalition there that
could be built upon by certain
candidates i think jesse ventura was
would be a great candidate that
kind of gets from both ends he gets from
the left he also gets from the the more
independent-minded libertarian chelsea
gabbard was able to
do the same while she was campaigning
for the presidency but i think what
we're seeing here is fascism of the left
and the fascism of the right are
entirely
tools of the establishment the left the
liberal left i would say loves to call
out the the right as being fascists love
to say donald trump is a fascist what
they fail to realize is both democrats
and republicans are consistently
getting rid of abs corpus they're
completely
diminishing the power that we have the
individual freedoms that we have as
people and they use the idea the facade
of national security and safety to do
that we're seeing that happen right now
because there's a pandemic and they can
easily use that excuse to infringe upon
our civil liberties and that's a very
dangerous thing that's happening and i
think it's something that more people on
the left on the socialist left need to
sort of pay attention to because i'm not
really seeing it i'm seeing it more on
on the independent libertarian side and
i think there's something to be uh said
about that and something to explore for
whoever next that we
support as either president congress
whatever they should be talking about
your civil liberties they should be
talking about
the election integrity they should be
talking about the issues that nobody's
talking about right now the fact that
our system is set up to make your vote
not count it is it is it is jumping
through hoops to simply cast a vote
americans are very lazy when it comes to
participation in our political system
also because of the fact that this is
how the system makes it it makes you
uh it's better for the the establishment
that you don't pay attention that you're
overworked so
yeah
so john um as someone that's
personally
experienced the power of the national
security state and someone that's
involved in
uh traditional media structure um what
do you think are some good ways that we
could try to
coalesce people into like a
post-partisan dialogue about um civil
liberties like free speech about privacy
and and things like that
good question tough question
um
i was thinking a minute ago that uh you
know we've we've got to push some of
these
leaders on the left and the right people
like bernie sanders because ron wyden's
not going to be around forever and we
can't put all of our eggs
in the baskets of ron wyden and mike lee
and uh and rand paul it's just not going
to get us anywhere so with that said um
you know i feel like
like the alternative media is gaining a
foothold that i've never seen before
i for one
get my news from the likes of consortium
news and reader supported news and and
outlets like that um i scan outlets on
the left and the right and and i've
gotten to the point where i rarely go to
the mainstream media
i think i'm not alone in that i think
that that's a trend and i think that
that's where we we need to go
with that said
what we lack
uh most importantly is money
uh we you know let me tell you a short
story in 2016 i traveled to 12 states
with gary johnson who was the
libertarian
nominee for president that year
and one of the things he told me and he
mentioned it very offhandedly
that really stuck with me
was that the libertarian party does not
have a benefactor
there was a family in california that
made its money in canned tomatoes he
said that had been very generous but in
terms of an actual ongoing benefactor
there just wasn't one
the democrats and the republicans have
hundreds of such benefactors well it's
the same thing with the alternative
media
we need a benefactor whether that media
is on the left or the right because it's
one thing to write for these outlets
it's another thing for the news to
actually get out there for people to
actually see it i feel like i write my
fingers to the bone right i write op-eds
at least every week i try to pump out
books as frequently as i can and that's
not unusual there are a lot of people
that do that but if nobody has access to
the
to the sites nobody's gonna nobody's
gonna get the news nobody's gonna be
informed the way we think people ought
to be informed and i think that one of
the things we need to do
is to um find ourselves one or two or 50
of these benefactors certainly we're not
the the only people uh in america
thinking this way
um i have a question kind of for all the
guests i mean given with what we've
discussed then exactly you know how
important
you know if you could convey to people
is it that we free julian assange you
know that we that we work for this free
press to get that out i mean and this is
for all the guests anybody who wants to
touch on that i i think it's very
important because the precedent that is
being set here
is chilling in terms of its effect on
free speech and on whistleblowers
and people who want to publish
what the
whistleblowers tell them
and what it's going to lead to is
a society where you can only be a
whistleblower if you have the approval
of adam's shift or yeah
on the other side devin devin nunes who
uh i don't know how many of you followed
his uh voting record before
he became the great defender of civil
liberties when the president or
president of his own party was the
target of the deep state but
he never really expressed that much
concern with uh overreach and massive
government surveillance when it was just
uh
anti-war activists and even anti-tax and
tea party activists that were being
targeted by the deep state
yeah i mean i agree with that i mean i
think it's important
that we set a precedent for
alternative media because mainstream
media is a propaganda machine now for
for the for the military industrial
complex and for the intelligence
community they control what everybody
the majority of the population in our
country sees hears and believes and no
matter how hard we try we are at a
disadvantage in money and networking and
reach as independent media and so
when
there is
such
misinformation and propaganda and
mis-education of people you're going to
get a population
that doesn't see that they're walking
right into slaughter and that's where
we're at and we're slowly creeping up as
independent media the only issue i have
with like um well let me just first say
julian assange whoever is the president
or whoever we start putting our support
by needs to be
pro
protecting whistleblowers they
absolutely 100 need to be because our
freedom of speech
is
one of the most important things that we
have as a society and it's one of the
things that america has always valued
itself i have a freedom of speech of
saying things you might disagree with
this is why i've always been against
censorship even if it came from somebody
like alex jones it like
once they started doing that they
started going after everybody
and so um we need to be very like
proactive in how we are going to handle
that because right now they're just
going to label people as russian assets
etc and i think whoever else we support
uh for any sort of politics has to be
have that in the front of their mind
they have to be
protecting our our
our truth tellers and that's that's what
has to be pushed i don't see that being
pushed on the left as much as it should
be i think you know this last election
kind of is showing that but even people
like tulsi gabbard um and other
progressives are not really like when it
comes to like civil liberties so like
you know they'll say oh we have to
protect people first and that's kind of
something that i'm
wary of when it comes to politicians
they're just not really on it and i
think it'll come from independent media
like you guys and us and
you know because it is our livelihood
too it's our lives that depend on
standing up for people like julian
assange and other whistleblowers
josh
go ahead andrew no i was just gonna i
was just gonna ask john if you wanted uh
yeah i i actually would this is
something i've been trying to talk about
a lot in the the last uh several weeks
uh one of the things that just
flabbergasts me
is
our seeming inability to convince the
likes of the washington post and the new
york times and other mainstream outlets
that if julian is convicted they're next
you know they they think that well
donald trump's not going to be around
forever he might not even be around for
more than another eight months
but
we saw under the obama administration
uh mainstream journalists described as
unindicted co-conspirators by the
attorney general of the united states we
saw raids on the homes of of working
mainstream journalists if they refused
to stand up and admit
publicly that julian assange is a
journalist and a publisher
there's literally nothing to stop the
government from targeting them next
it's as simple as that
and that's to that point that's why
um the special administrative measures
within the united states really reveal
is the true power that the federal
government holds that it can push down
against any individual that it chooses
because it's something that
um they basically said yes julian will
be placed under special administrative
measures when he gets here which
basically completely limits access to
his attorney access to information and a
bunch of other
just heinous things across the board
including 23 hours a day if not more of
solitary confinement
um
could you talk a little bit norm or do
you kind of have a perspective on um
ways in general that we can push back
against
projects or not projects but policies
like sam's and other
criminal injustices that happen inside
of our justice system
there are so many different
organizations doing great work out there
i work very closely for example with the
human rights defense center which also
publishes prison legal news and criminal
legal news magazines
so there are a lot of us out there
working
kind of
independently of one another if we if we
can figure out a way to work together
and to harness the power that we have i
think we'll be far more impactful uh
right now we're generally ignored by the
mainstream media
but i mean everything from these events
like the one we're doing right now which
i find to be very beneficial and i'm i'm
always surprised at how many uh people
watch these and go to them later on
youtube it's very heartening but we need
to find a way to work
together in a more integrated fashion so
that we can get the word out and that we
don't look like you know just some guy
or some woman standing off to the side
outside of julian's trial yelling about
civil liberties
we have important things to say and you
know people who have who have
legitimate experiences that the media
really need to focus on uh they're
they're on point with julian and i think
uh
i think we've got a story to tell i i
think that um there is some room for
optimism the fact that there is an
alternative media today the fact that um
there are organizations like campaign
for liberty like the ron paul institute
on the libertarian side um the fact that
dr paul is a daily program that is doing
quite well telling some of the truth
about the
brontovirus
and how crazy it is that we basically
shut down the entire economy for a virus
that uh
you probably have a less
than one percent chance of dying unless
you are have a pre-existing condition
um but uh
and also
going back to something we talked about
before this what happened last week in
the senate
we came within one vote of getting put
into law that you have to get a warrant
now
silly me i thought that there was this
thing called the fourth amendment that
already put the warrant requirement in
the lobby for the government to take
your your seizure papers and records
but
i guess uh that went out that actually
went out with the war on drugs back in
the 80s and 90s
under uh especially under george the
first
attorney general william barr
that name may ring a bell with some of
you
but anyway uh
that was actually when you consider
where we were just 10 years ago
on
this
bill that uh
the first
indication that he wasn't going to be
nearly as good on foreign policy and
civil liberties as president as he was
on the campaign trail
voted for
the fish bill in 08 and it was basically
widely acknowledged that this was just a
political move on his part because he
didn't think he could vote against it
where today
you see people on both sides lining up
to vote for a wide danes amendment you
have a very liberal senator and you have
a very conservative senator
libertarianist senator coming together
to stop warrantless wiretapping and they
almost won even though mcconnell set a
60-vote threshold
this is progress uh some other things
we're making progress on foreign policy
on the republican party
uh donald trump did what ron paul tried
to do
and um
back in the 90s pat buchanan tried to do
which is run a successful campaign in
the republican primary challenging
conventional neoconservative wisdom
and running as the avowed enemy of bill
crystal
and dr paul did better than anyone could
could have expected
his son has done better than anyone
could have expected in his career
but then also look at donald trump in
2016. he stood up before a republican
primary debate and said that going into
iraq was a horrible mistake and he
actually called out george bush in front
of his brother
and he not only survived he went on to
get the nomination
so there is a
a groundswell of support of questioning
of foreign policy of civil liberties and
of the federal reserve
which ought to be something that
libertarians and progressives can join
together on because the federal reserve
is as daniel mcadams once brilliantly
called it the dark heart of the welfare
warfare state we can argue about the
welfare state but let's let's work
together on getting rid of the warfare
state and let's at least get rid of the
corporate welfare state
uh i think it's it's about time that um
one thing that kind of annoys me about
republicans is when the farm bill comes
up every four or five years republicans
get up and stand up and scream about we
need to
to get
single mothers off the dole so we need
to put work requirements into the the
food stamp stamp program or the ebt
program
and then they'll shovel several uh
billions of subsidies to millionaire
farmers most of whom don't even have
never even walked on
on a real farm
and there's something that i think
there's there should be room for
convergence on the left right
convergence on libertarian and
progressive convergence on is um let's
at least get rid of the welfare for the
rich and then we can talk about
what's it what what
provisions
the society could make for the poor and
if i could just be engaged i apologize
for rambling but i have a lot of
these these topics excite me as you
might might be able to tell
uh somebody said the libertarians are
against the social
safety net that's actually not true
libertarians are against at least a
federal government-provided social
safety net
for a variety of reasons one of which is
that the federal government
as we are seeing now can't even
send out checks
to people without a screwing it up and b
making sure that the big guys the
produce the the fat cats are taken care
of and the little and the average person
gets some crumbs
and is supposed to be grateful for that
no that's a that's a good point and i've
i've said forever that i support the
idea of a
universal health care system i just
don't want
congress running it
andrew makes the point that like if the
national nurses union was in charge of
universal health care that would put us
in a much better position than say uh
you know chuck schumer and mitch
mcconnell
even in this situation right now
volunteer is in charge of our health
care yeah yeah and we've got palantir in
char running uh running the health care
of the you know partnered up with the
nhs in the uk as well and when peter
thiel is running the show
the only person that wins or the only
entity that wins is an ever increasing
surveillance state
when i pause dramatically like that
that's someone's cue to hop in
john you've been on before
[Laughter]
so one of the big things
oh no go ahead v i'm sorry oh no i was
just gonna say um
you know like i i think people don't
care
who runs it um
as long as it happens other countries
have a
not necessarily medicare for all but a
nationalized type of health care system
and they are able to manage it
accordingly i don't think it's a matter
of congress being unable to it's a
matter of congress not wanting to
because the money and the lobbyists are
there um i i don't necessarily trust the
government to run it but i think if we
were to appoint the right people to run
a health care system where there was no
middleman where you could just have
basic health care for everybody and then
you could buy
um supplemental whatever i like if you
wanted something else
um you still have the choice to do that
if you'd if you'd like but i think i
think it's important that
we
the argument that the government is
going to infringe they're doing it right
now when we have a private
uh health insurance
industry they're they're doing it right
now it doesn't matter i i don't think
it's going to hurt us to
go towards a universal health care
system we just have to find what works
for
our country because our our states we're
obviously a different country than like
say denmark and it's going to take a
sort of different process for it
well one thing to keep in mind about
um
the affordable health care act or
obamacare
as it's become widely known is that
uh my friend tim harney at the
washington examiner who does great work
on the uh corporates
how big business benefits from the
welfare
and regulatory state uh has pointed out
that
while obama was out in the rose garden
demonizing the insurance industry for
fighting against his health care plan
insurance industry lobbyists were
sitting back in the west wing with
obama's staffers writing the bill and
when people say oh big insurance was
against obama care i say right because
big businesses would naturally hate a
law that says that it is a crime for you
to fail to purchase my product
so this is something a parallel to that
that was seen in julian's case
um when they were in court early on here
after he'd been taken into belmarsh the
the judge who was supposed to be this
neutral arbiter of this
um globally impacting press freedom case
walks to the back of the room to meet
with the americans that are there
um so it's this level of corruption
whether it exists in like a corporate
state or within the
um larger institutions of the i would
say the privatized police state at this
point
um but john if you could because you
have the most experience in handling
these kinds of situations
firsthand and like litigation against
the government being prosecuted for
proliferating truth could you talk a
little bit about
what julian actually faces i know we've
gone over it before but just to kind of
lay it out again
sure
sure um julian faces
um a very tough experience in the
eastern district of virginia
uh
and frankly much of that is just because
he's headed to the eastern district of
virginia
um i've told this story before but i
think it bears repeating
in the eastern district here in
alexandria virginia is known as the
espionage court because
that's where the government likes to
file most of its uh its national
security charges i was charged here
julian's charged here ed snowden's
charged here
jeffrey sterling was charged here
and no national security defendant has
ever won a case in the eastern district
now i predicted for a long time wrongly
as it turned out that julian's judge
would be judge leonie brinkuma who
usually reserves these national security
cases for herself it turned out that
brinkama had the case taken away from
her
by the chief judge who just happens to
have been
a fisa court judge before he was named
to the eastern district
that makes me want to run screaming from
the room
we also know that that the government
intends to invoke something called sipa
the control the i'm sorry the classified
information
uh protection act
so what they're gonna do
is they're going to clear the courtroom
they're going to
cover the windows and the doors with
plastic sheeting and duct tape so no one
can
aim a laser beam at the windows and pick
up the vibrations and hear
what classified conversations are taking
place inside the courtroom everyone will
be dismissed except uh the prosecutors
and julian
the i'm sorry the prosecutors the the
defense attorneys and julian the clerk
and the bailiff and the jury and that's
it nobody else will be allowed in the
room
furthermore
the judge is going to issue a list of
words
um
to the jury that will replace words that
the prosecution alleges are classified
so let's say the word
nsa is cla or the acronym nsa is
classified
maybe they'll call it um zebra or
swimming pool so anytime someone needs
to refer to nsa they won't say nsa
they'll say zebra and there's going to
be a little paper that the jury has and
it'll say nsa equals zebra so they can
follow along and understand what the
heck is being said
in the courtroom it's a ridiculous
exercise and frankly i've always
maintained that it serves to bias the
jury against the defendant because the
implication is even these interval
individual words are so
highly classified
that we can't even utter them
in this closed courtroom so he must be
guilty he must be a bad guy he must have
done all these terrible wrong things so
we have to convict him
uh
with that said
no let me add one more thing
from my own experience and again i've
told the story before but it bears
repeating
um
when i was headed to trial i hired o.j
simpson's jury consultant
uh he was the is the um
the father of my best friend's wife
and so he did it for free the man's
never lost a case he represented george
zimmerman in the trayvon martin shooting
he represented uh besides oj uh william
kennedy smith in his rape case the guys
never lost a case literally he's never
lost a case
and so he came up to washington he lives
in dallas
and we got him a security clearance from
the justice department and he went
through the files my files
fifteen thousand pages of discovery
and
when it was all over we sat in the um
not when it was over but when he had
finished going through the files we sat
in my attorney's uh conference room
and he said look here's the bottom line
if we were in any other district in
america i would say let's go for it
we're going to win this thing
but the eastern district of virginia he
said you don't have a chance
he said your jury is going to be made up
of employees or family members of
employees of the cia the pentagon the
department of homeland security uh the
fbi
intelligence community contractors he
said you don't have a chance
it's all stacked against you that's why
they charged you here in the first place
he said my advice to you is to take the
deal and i took the deal
well julian's not likely to be offered a
deal
the the whole point of julian's case is
to make an example of him because this
case is far bigger than just julian
assange this case is about media and
media freedom
and so long as the mainstream media
decides that julian is somehow their
enemy and doesn't come out in their
editorial pages every single day day
after day to support him
uh i i think that a very bad precedent
is going to be said said here now i've
said in the past that i think the one
chance he has in the eastern district um
is is the chance of jury nullification
there has to be one
right thinking person out there
you know out of what's a jury 12 people
at the federal level nine people 12
people i don't know
i never made it to a jury but there's
got to be one person out there
who can think independently and and
conclude that this is just wrong
this whole prosecution is wrong the case
is wrong the man has already suffered
and it has to end
um that's not much to hang your hat on
but
i struggle every day thinking
what we can do to make it better and i'm
not coming up with a lot of ideas
i mean that that kind of inspires me to
uh
something that adam kokesh had talked
about in one of our previous visuals i
think where it was the way that
people choose to educate other people
about certain issues and how
there's not any group using jury
nullification as a standing point for
their hill to project to the world
um
do you think that
starting some kind of educational
campaign in the eastern district of
virginia about jury nullification uh
would be effective do you think that
would i do i do indeed and you know i've
raised this with a number of attorney
friends
who who said that i was crazy that jury
nullification uh is is illegal
that uh you can't encourage jury
nullification i said i'm an independent
citizen i'm not an attorney standing up
in court and saying
jury nullification right i'm allowed to
have an opinion and i think that there's
a role for jury nullification look you
know at one time it was legal for
six-year-olds to work in the mines now
it's not
sometimes laws are just bad laws the
espionage act is one of them so i think
that there is a role for jury
nullification
does that look like going around
foggy bottom strip malls putting copies
of the nils melter interview under
people's windshields like
i'm not opposed to that i'll go do that
there used to be a group called the
fully informed jury association fijia
i'm not sure if they're
still around or how active they are but
they used but one of their projects was
having people stand outside the
courthouse and hand out flyers
um targeting potential jurors informing
them of their right to judge on the
facts and the law
so it has been done
i think the uh the libertarian party at
one point was very much behind this
effort as well
i kind of i'd kind of like to get your
reaction norm to uh to
john's uh
john's story and the knowledge that he
dropped in it was this stuff that you
were already aware of having worked in
dc and been a part of that scene
or uh
well i i actually think i heard john
discuss this
the the problems with the eastern
district of uh
virginia on sputnik uh radio one day
um and now i just doubted myself is
clearly i'm a russian agent because
obviously why else would i be listening
to uh
just but um
but uh
but i wasn't i was not aware of the the
eastern district uh problem until i
heard uh i heard john talk about it um
and i don't think a lot of people are
aware are aware of that but everything
he said makes sense and it certainly
makes sense in terms of the jury pool
that you're going to be looking for
you're going to be drawing because of
the nature of it from people who are
government contractors people at the
pentagon
and
they're in that culture
um that they believe that they are in
the right that they are protecting
america and that people like julian
assange chelsea manning edward snowden
and john are
bad people who are disloyal to the
greatest country in the history of the
world
i have a question for fiorella i'm
wondering what um
what do you hit the most as like
roadblocks for civil liberties and for
you know like the situation of julian
assange within the left like what are
some of the biggest roadblocks that you
see there because like just even from
what we were talking about you know
we're looking at basically
you know a secret court not being able
to know what's going on i mean for the
public to me this is also really bad for
our civil liberties not to know what's
going on
in the biggest
um
you know free press case of our lifetime
yeah i mean i think the biggest
roadblock is the fact that progressives
especially the like progressives um who
consider themselves ultra leftist
do not consider this a big issue um it's
definitely not
one of their main concerns and it's
something that it it should be a main
concern but like what i see with people
i know on the left they really like this
is probably last on their list and
because they look at immediate concerns
they're looking at the immediacy of a
health care system failing they're
looking at the immediacy of being unable
to pay rent they're looking at all these
issues and in in a sense it's it's sort
of a catch-22 because those two things
work against each other you guys know
pasta pasta is um
he was a tulsi supporter primarily
because he supported civil liberties and
foreign policy above everything else my
belief is that we should support both of
them but at the same time it's like
you're not in my opinion it's really
hard to get people's attention to
something like julian assange if they
can't see the immediate concern so like
if people are too busy like working you
know for jobs and they can't pay their
bills
they're really not going to care about
people being bombed abroad in different
countries just as much as they're really
not going to care about what happens to
one guy they're not looking at the
bigger picture as to wow this has so
much of a precedent and it's so much
effect so it's going to affect us for
years and years and years because we're
not paying attention to the biggest case
regarding freedom of speech in our
lifetime and it's really hard i think
there has to be like work in tandem we
have to address like the concerns a lot
of the working people have
while being like look people aren't
going to hear your concerns the
government is free to do
whatever they want and abuse you
because we don't have real like
journalism in america we
we have uh the fourth at stock was
supposed to be
like for the people it was supposed to
be the fourth branch of government and
right now it's just a propaganda machine
for the military and the intelligence
community and so if we can make people
realize that they're not going to get
all of these domestic issues and these
concerns if they don't also pay
attention to foreign policy and the uh
civil liberties that are being
constantly infringed upon us on the
daily
then we could probably make that
connection you know what i mean we have
to make that connection because they're
not listening to you when you're talking
about julian assange because they're
looking at it as like okay well that's
him that's a separate case no it's all
connected and we have to look
and kind of highlight exactly why
everything is connected
something i've found to be effective at
least on a person-to-person basis and
then through through my show that i
really don't hear a lot in media in
general is that your cause
is [__] dead
without the ability to access free and
free and open information your
whatever whatever it is you're into
whatever's on the front of your sign if
it doesn't have free julian assange on
the back of it
you're doing your organizing wrong
because if we don't have the ability to
get this information out there
regardless of what it is
it's dead it goes nowhere you're talking
to the three people that you know about
it that already know about it
well look i i would say look at the ron
paul campaigns of 08 2012 particularly
in oa
when it started
it was a very very took advantage of
meetup of facebook and myspace if
anybody remembers myspace
and youtube and all of those
platforms that were at the time much
more open to dissident ideas
and
organized shared videos shared articles
by dr paul
and got the word out there
as an idea of what grassroots can
accomplish unfortunately today you have
these big tech companies in bed with the
national security state
and we see
the the d platforming going on the
censorship the constant problems with uh
youtube
demonetizing um
certain voices
but it's still but we still have this
ability we can still find alternatives
we can still get the word out to people
and again
you can always go back to your
representative who is under our
constitutional system there's a reason
why there are more representatives than
there are presidents and senators and
there's a reason why they're up for
election every two years as opposed to
every six or every four that's because
they're supposed to be
closest to
to us and the senators are supposed to
be second in terms of being responsive
to the people and i think that it's a
problem
with political activists across the
board that they kind of focus on what
the executive is doing and they ignore
the fact that in our constitutional
system the president is not supposed to
be the king
uh the president is supposed to be
actually accountable to the executive
branch when they wrote the constitution
they knew what they knew
they numbered the branches one
legislative two executive three
judiciary for a reason and i think we've
forgotten that i think that is one
reason why
uh we are losing our liberties to a man
with executive state
and
the only argument seems to be right now
is which grumpy old man
is fit to have this incredible power of
donald trump or joe biden
and i think too
in the activist communities there's a
lot or there's a lot of talk about
censorship
where you have the left pointing out the
censorship on the left and you have the
right pointing out the censorship on the
right
but it's hard to find
people on either side that are willing
to say
both are censored and there are some
that do
um and you guys over a combo couch do a
great job of this of pointing out just
the [__] and the hypocrisy that
exists between
the two dynamics um but one of the
things
going back to the idea of building
um
like a post ideological conversation
like building people up around issues
that are fundamental um i think
censorship and the fight for a free and
open internet's one of those really big
things
um could you talk about that a little
bit fee about um like experiences you
guys have had with internet censorship
that
you know may be from a big platform or
maybe one of those like coincidences
that something happened when it did
oh yeah absolutely i mean we're being
censored left and right all of our
videos that deal with anything regarding
um
intelligence agencies anything regarding
a military-industrial complex any
mention of syria any mention of any sort
of foreign policy issue venezuela all of
that gets entirely censored i it's also
not as popular like whenever we were
talking about election integrity um it
is a kind of a wonky subject so a lot of
people like it's hard to like get them
to tune in but that's some of the things
that we've experienced are like our uh
likes being scrubbed off people being
unsubscribed our video our technology
just seeming not to work
uh at certain times and i and i know
that this happens because youtube is
owned by google so like i know that they
have their preferences we also notice uh
my friend nico
noticed how like they were
like if you if you were going to find
one of his videos
if he searched it using this one program
he did it said it should be one of the
top videos but in reality on youtube it
doesn't appear you have to search every
single word for our videos to appear so
it's the suppression is real and it's
actually known that this is a thing that
they can legally do
so that's why we're trying to look at
alternative
like video sites like rockfin
that
are more people
like you know people friendly they're
more like a co-op type of model where
you still can make money off of it but
you're not putting your
viewers through so much stress and
they're not subjected to ads and it's a
little bit different and i think we need
to find alternatives in media
and and to to kind of take away from
youtube and i think youtube's time is
definitely ending but i definitely see a
lot of the you know the censorship also
like in la
we
we only have two providers we have
either spectrum which bought time warner
or we have
directv which is another corporation and
i think the majority of people
use spectrum and in some parts they have
att which is also uh another another
thing that we we use as well and that's
it you don't have access to internet
from a different location and if your
area is not beverly hills beverly hills
for instance has fiber optic internet
they have the fastest internet and the
city of beverly hills can have that
because they're rich and they put all
their resources there whereas where i
live in pasadena it's it's not the
poorest but it's also not the richest
and so
you know we were uh ron pacone myself
pasta we all went to a city council
meeting to push for
uh just municipal internet and basically
the atnt lobbyist was there telling the
city council to that this just wouldn't
work and they made up a reason as to why
it wouldn't work but obviously it was
money involved and um we have to find
ways creative ways and there's new
technology coming up of creating our own
networks creating our own ability to
promote independent media i don't like
the idea of somebody mentioned like
just one provider i don't like that idea
because i i'm against centralized
government
um i think a centralized structure in
anything could be capitulate could be
co-opted into a powerful powerful
person having
too much power whether like i tyt is an
example of that they started out
progressive
um quote unquote and then they slowly
you know started getting these people on
their board that were
venture capitalists and had other
interests and you saw the reporting
change a way to avoid that is to have a
decentralized structure
um in in whatever sort of co-op thing
media can form and i think obviously
it's going to require people putting in
money to it but it should be in a way
that is very transparent
that doesn't mimic the way the
establishment is
so i want to thank our guests for
joining us um we do have to move to our
news segment
um but if you could um i'll start with
norm uh could you let people know where
to find you your work and the
organization you're involved with
uh campaign for liberty
campaignforliberty.com
it is a 501c4 grassroots lobbying
organization our major issues are audit
the fed
repeal the patriot act
um
free market health care
that lets doctors and patients not
government bureaucrats or insurance
agencies control
the uh
their health care and uh basically just
the entire bill of rights from the first
all the way up through the through
through the 10th we were founded by dr
ron paul he was
and i really appreciate being being on
here and uh everybody's time and i hope
everyone stays involved and active in
whatever way you feel you can best
contribute to the important cause of
protecting our
liberties
thank you thank you very much again
um and if you could
um
let us know your final thoughts fee and
where people can find you and the
wonderful work you do
yeah thank you guys for doing this um a
lot of people aren't really covering
julia's julian assange as much and i
always get all my news from all of you
guys so thank you for doing this and
sticking with it
i will help out and promote you guys
wherever i can my name is fiorella
isabel i have a twitter fiorella
underscore i am
the uh channel we have is the convo
couch
um spelled just like combo conversation
and couch and you can find us on youtube
on rockfin we also have a facebook
instagram and twitter so thank you guys
so much appreciate you
thank you
don't bother we said hey
i will i will
um so do you want to do you want to run
news in order uh that it is on the
dock there
yeah yeah i think cause it's it's pretty
well set up okay josh if you could grab
that guardian article we can
go into it
mike pompeo
okay and y'all gotta be you by now
by now hopefully you know that if
there's an opportunity to kick around
mike pompeo i'm i'm going to jump up and
and take it um this is pretty this is a
case where mike pompeo is doing the
kicking uh
although we'll get into
why it uh it may backfire the trump
administration has fired the state
department's inspector general who is
reported to have been investigating
secretary of state mike pompeo for
potential abuse of office
the inspector general steve linnick was
given notice of the dismissal late on
friday night and is expanded ah jesus
and is to be replaced by stephen ackerd
a close ally of the vice president mice
mike pence from his home state of
indiana mine there's a funny little
sidebar here not funny because it's mike
pence and the guy is really like as
funny as a bus full of dead babies but
but funny in that i grew up in the
district what mike pence wound up
representing now this is not my fault
because i was already gone
but uh
mike pence used to be a radio guy and
his tagline for his radio show was that
he was like rush limbaugh on decaf and
that was enough for the people of the
6th congressional district to be of
indiana to be like yeah that's our guy
we'll we'll take that guy
um back to the article a state
department spokesman said that acard
who'd been running the office for
foreign missions would take over
immediately as acting ig
according to a democratic congressional
aide just before his abrupt dismissal
lineage had opened an investigation into
allegations that pompeo had been using a
political appointee at state to run
personal errands for him and his wife
susan
let's pause for a moment
just to recognize how perfect it is that
mrs pompeo is a susan
moving on
now go ahead andrew you want to say
something
no i just wanna just take a moment to
reflect on the fact that mike pompeo has
a politically politically appointed
personal assistant
that like someone had to make that
decision like yep this dude is your
personal assistant mike pompeo
i just find that
i just find that absolutely ridiculous
yeah
and the you would yeah
so
under u.s law the president is required
to give 30 days notice before firing an
inspector general to allow congress to
investigate the reasons for dismissal in
recent months congress has not used that
month-long notice period to prevent the
termination of other watchdog officials
fired by the president um
lennock is the latest in a string of
officials in watchdog roles fired by the
president in recent months turning on
its head the tradition that such jobs
are filled with non-partisan figures
trump has demanded personal loyalty from
officials working in the administration
especially those in an oversight role
um
linux is not the first inspector general
to be fired late on a friday night on
april 3rd this year trump dismissed
intelligence community inspector general
michael atkinson who had first deemed
credible a whistleblower complaint
expressing concern about trump's call
last summer to his ukrainian counterpart
vladimir zelinski
which ultimately triggered impeachment
proceedings against the press president
can we talk about this for a minute
because
this is absolute like hot steaming
[__] on a freaking cold pasture
mourn
yeah i wanted to pause here because i
don't inherently disagree
with the fact that that other guy was
fired uh the dude that was spreading the
[__] about the
was a whistleblower who should have all
these protections and it allowed
people to see the connection between the
state censorship apparatus and the um
global media platforms because if you
said the person's name jason or eric
caramello bar your video gets removed
and i still can't say the guy's name so
i'm stealing jason burma's
little tagline for him um
so i think that's always super important
to say when impeachment comes up is that
it was [__] and it was used as a way
to exercise in enforcement of technology
at the behest of the government to
remove particular content from the
internet in a very aggressive fashion
well that and then also i don't know
what you guys think about this but with
all the things to investigate pompeo for
you know like this is what we're
settling on
this is what the oversight committee is
interested in this is
this is just
when however you pronounce his last name
um he was
basically an investigator all the way
through his career
but um during his tenure at the
department of justice he supervised and
participated in white collar criminal
fraud cases involving corruption and
contract fraud against the us and iraq
and afghanistan
and ju as a as we know through
the washington post release of the
afghan papers in late 2019
which did
100 percent uh codify and
just validate everything that wikileaks
had put out nearly a decade earlier
afghanistan and iraq is based on grift
like that's
what what keeps us there that's why we
went in the first place it's one of the
biggest
transnational fraud scams in history um
and and to give him credit david mcbride
is facing 50 years in prison right now
for exposing that grift in australia
um he released documents and i don't a
lot of people remember some people never
heard
but the abc news the australian
broadcasting center um was rated to have
these documents seized and removed by
australian federal police
because australia doesn't have a first
amendment protection so the federal
police are allowed to just completely
charge in
alter news records and take documents
directly from journalists and it was
david mcbride's release of information
that showed the politicization of the
iraq war or the afghanistan war that
caused those raids to happen
oh if we could circle back real quick
though to the not a whistleblower
whistleblower and the ukraine thing we
just found out today that there's tape
of joe biden
bribing the freaking pros ukrainian
prosecutor to drop the burisma case and
his son holding against his son holding
a billion dollars over his head and it's
on tape and joey [__] b
goes now
he doesn't come out and say i'm bribing
you but he's like you understand what
this is for a you know and it's on
[__] day
and like
imagine just imagine for a second that
donald trump was caught on a hot mic
going now i'm not bribing you but here's
a bag of cash and i'm pretty sure you
know what to do with it right
like can you imagine the field day
that every single one of those
bedwetting npr liberals would have over
this lay and there's crickets
in
mainstream media about this about this
tape
crickets this
further proves that the not a
whistleblower whistleblower
isn't a whistleblower but in fact was a
guy following orders from the cia the
last time that we had john kiriakou on
this show
in fact he was john was the one who was
like look there's only two reasons that
you become the cia liaison to the white
house and it's because you are a
wide-eyed
go-getter
very early on in his career or your
erica calamari caramelo bar who is
a a someone who's on his way to another
position and earned the right to a
two-year soft detail at the white house
well not to mention that i think too i
mean when you go into the ukraine thing
i mean obviously even the fact that they
went to impeach trump over ukraine
showed even then not that most people
didn't know
that russiagate was complete nonsense
and now we have that proven
even more and yet people still don't
know about it and i think that's part of
what happens here with with trump and
that whole you know fake news and
everything like that to really get
through
a different policy that has nothing to
do with the elected president let me
tell you what happened so in 2016 the
chicago cubs broke their curse and they
won the world series first time in like
108 years or something like that and
after that russia gate broke and people
were like well [__] it the cubs won
beating a dead horse is now america's
favorite pastime so we've got russiagate
and we can do that forever and ever and
ever and ever and ever
long may it way
that's i and if somebody has a better
explanation only goddamn here well the
funniest part
and this is before i get back in because
i want to read trump's letter to pelosi
but the funniest part about the
russiagate thing
is that
the
the anti-communist
boomers
don't believe russiagate
that's the part that cracks me up like
the pro-trump boomer generation that was
raised during the
the height of the red scare
don't believe the pro-russian propaganda
yeah and all the free love [__]
hippies
are like i'm bringing in new mccarthyism
baby it's we live in a cartoon it's the
biggest paradox like i think uh i want
to say his name is robert reich
released a video talking about how
literally talking about the history of
how mccarthy used the red scare as a way
to gain power
to justify
the red scare that they were putting on
with um
the russia gate so it was just like the
whole
like complex of like the anti-russia
anti-communists not supporting the
anti-russia campaign was just that blew
my mind
but i do
so
this representative um linux or
president trump i'm sorry wrote a letter
to nancy pelosi about linux getting
fired and i just want to read it in its
full context
um it says dear speaker pelosi this is
to arrive as i am exercising my power as
president to remove from office the
inspector general of the department of
state
effective 30 days from today it is
extremely important that we promote the
economy efficiency and effectiveness of
federal programs and activities the
inspector general
the inspectors general have a critical
role in the achievement of these goals
as is the case with regards to other
positions where i the president have the
power to appoint by and with the advice
and consent of the senate it is vital
that i have the fullest confidence in
the appointees serving as inspector
general it is no longer the case with
regard to this inspector general um
at a later date i will submit to the
senate my nomination of an individual
for this position who has my fullest
confidence to meet the appropriate
qualifications
so not really much to be said there it's
not like a
ground-breaking thing but i just wanted
to make sure that that got put in there
because those were
the official words of trump to pelosi in
regards to that
i suppose if if you're the president of
the united states and you're never going
to be anything more
than the public relations space for the
oligarchy because that's all a president
is
then you would want to remind
uh
i guess your subordinates
that you're the president all the time
because trump always finds a way to work
that in like oh and by the way i'm the
president so i get to do this like not
only do i get two scoops of ice cream
every day but i get to fire inspectors
generals and sometimes they let me sit
in the truck and let me honk the ward
like
it's a [__] job that's my point that's
what i'm trying to get at
um
we want to go to uh the consortium news
article now
absolutely you want to take this one
kendra
yeah sure do you want um i'll just start
at the beginning um
a scandinavian activist group has opened
signatures for an appeal to the swedish
government for a full and transparent
investigation into a possible
disappearance of documents and the
illegal destruction of evidence in the
swedish prosecutors and police probe of
sexual allegations against julian
assange
the appeal also demands assange's
release from belmarsh prison in london
where he is on remand in an extradition
request by the united states on
espionage charges for unauthorized
possession and dissemination of
classified material it calls on sweden
to provide him asylum
the best investigation the appeal seeks
would also look into why assange's case
appears to have exceeded a statute of
limitations as well as into pressure
british authorities brought to bear on a
swedish prosecutor against assange
sweden has three times dropped the case
against the imprisoned wikileaks
publisher the appeal acts on the
findings of nils meltzer the united
nations special repertoire on torture
and other cruel inhuman
or degrading treatment who said swedish
police forged evidence in the case
against assange
um do you want me to go into the history
or read down to the
case what do you guys think
if we could i would say skip down to the
actual text itself at the bottom
okay
um or just said
oh i was just gonna say for anybody who
hasn't seen this article yet it's a
really great one it's another one of
those good
um articles to share with people too
because they they give a great breakdown
of the swedish case which i know most
people are familiar with but especially
someone who might not know it's a good
it's a good quick um breakthrough of
that so
the text of the appeal set julian
assange free
appeal to the swedish government
the whistleblower website wikileaks
founder julian assange is detained in
the british high security prison
belmarsh his health is in a critical
condition we the signatories of this
appeal fear for his life and mental
health due to the treatment he is
exposed to we demand his immediate
release respect for his fundamental
human rights a fair and transparent
judicial treatment and protection
against extradition to usa
the united nations special repertoire on
torture and other cruel inhumane or
degrading treatment niels meltzer
visited julian assange in prison on the
9th of may 2019 with a group of medical
doctors they concluded that assange
showed all symptoms that are typical
consequences of prolonged mental torture
we are deeply alarmed by the un findings
concerning assange's state of health and
of the legal proceedings he has been
subjected to in particular by the
swedish police from 2010 and onwards
that's just 2010
for a decade
assange was arrested for breach of bail
in the uk an act which is not a crime as
he feared extradition to sweden for
accusations of rape raised by the
swedish police meltzer holds that
assange's subsequent fear of extradition
to sweden and then further to the u.s
was well founded the u.n report argues
that this and a number of other serious
breaches of law may have been carried
out by the authorities during the
process against assange sweden has since
sweden has since it started this fall to
roll under the protection from torture
treaty cat a responsibility also for the
pain inflicted upon assange in belmarsh
and britain the swedish prosecutor and
police have refused to respond to claims
presented in a letter of the 12th of
september 2019
not to respond to the un report and the
serious accusations it presents is
unacceptable it undermines the authority
of the united nations and the public is
entitled to this information if respect
for judicial institutions is to be
upheld
we the signatories of this appeal find
the report of the united nations
repertoire on torture and of the un's
office on arbitrary detention deeply
alarming we demand the immediate release
of julian assange from british prison
and that he be granted asylum in sweden
or another country of his choice
guaranteed not to be extradited to the
us the present coronavirus threat
aggravates the situation even further
and makes his release even more pressing
did you guys want to jump in at all
before i keep going
i just want to i want to give this a
shout out before you get to the end of
it because i threw it in the
live chats for everybody too
there is a link at the bottom of this
article
that lets you actually go and sign on to
this appeal yourself on the original
signers of it
um were
john shipton noam chomsky
um
i believe julian's mom is on there eva
jody i know just a bunch of other
um wonderful wonderful well-known
and high-profile activists and things
like that
many politicians like there's a german
politician that's on there so if you
could please go i believe that set
julian free
is the website for that um let me just
double check though
it's a dot org i threw it in my chat too
yep um set julianfree.org so please go
and sign that because that is super
important to get as many signatures on
there as we possibly can
no i i agree with that you want to wrap
up the
the letter and then we'll
discuss and
whatnot yeah sure um
so the end of this uh
we further demand that the swedish
minister ministry of justice respond to
the allegations brought forth by the
said un authorities and instruct
appropriate swedish legal action be
taken for a full and transparent
investigation into a possible
disappearance of documents alleged by
the un report in order to clarify if or
to what extent a legal destruction of
evidence and perversion of the course of
justice has taken place a full and
transparent investigation into the why
the into why the case assange has been
into why the case against assange has
been stretched out over years when
swedish law sets a strict limit of
months for such proceedings a full and
transparent investigation into the
nature of cooperation between swedish
and british police with the alleged aim
of conducting extra-legal arrest
harassment and detention of julian
assange and with the possible aim of
extraditing him to a third country that
sweden respect the united nations by
fulfilling its obligations to enter
aliyah the following international
treaties of which it is a signatory
state the convention against torture and
other cruel inhuman or degrading
treatment or punishment um cat ratified
1986 the international covenant on civil
and political rights ccpr ratified in
1971. international law commission the
international wrongful act of the state
ilc and i was we finally demand that
julian assange be given a fair treatment
in accordance with principles of basic
human rights and the rule of law and
that any wrongdoings against him brought
about by representatives of the swedish
authorities be rectified and fully
compensated for in accordance with
swedish law
so that's the end of that and i in the
bottom here to andrew's point you know
some of the other people who signed on
were john pilger um yes john uh john
shipton julian's father noam chomsky um
nsa whistleblower tom drake german
journalist uh gunter walraf and former
u.n assistant secretary general dennis
holland halliday
and then everybody watching the vigil
tonight as well
every last one of you
please share this article around and
please share that link around most
specifically for
us julianfree.org because that is super
important to get people signing on to
that
and while you're in a link sharing mood
we're going to go ahead and put the
gofundme up one more time
um
because you know
three weeks in dc is a long time to
to
[Music]
well be away
and yeah
it's it's one of those things where
we went into uh we went into february
knowing it was going to be a learning
experience
and we learned a ton and we can't wait
to be able to roll it out onto the
streets of washington dc but we
definitely need your help to be able to
do that so if you can
please do donate if you can't we totally
get it please share the heck out of the
link
and please join us
because it is going to be a blast we're
in the the we've had four probably about
three or four like behind the scenes
organizer meetings
um and i'm just really excited to put
out the official dates and times and all
that for
when things are going on because it's
going to be
if we can pull it off right it's going
to be super impressive so i hope that it
it's a way that we can build attention
and momentum around this issue
but for this was actually an article
that um this next one that kendra had
recommended out of the medium
um
so let me get this pulled up here let me
know when it's up on screen josh
but this is the
uh assange's hell in the u.s
so this article really breaks down
um what we've learned recently about the
theft of documents from julian out of
the ecuadorian embassy the money that
got transferred and all that
um
do you want to pick this one up steve or
do you want to kendra
i got it give me just a second i'm uh
posting a link to our discord in my chat
um and by the way guys it is in the
action document as well okay this week's
list of actions
so uh
this is by jude fleming it was it
dropped two days ago
uh and it says the unimaginable happened
to julian assange on april 11 2019. the
day of betrayal when he was abducted by
british police then transferred to a
high security prison on behalf of the
united states the bail breach infraction
was a ruse for the immediate gold
putting him in proxy custody for the u.s
but it got worse
ecuadorian officials received a u.s
request for us for access to assange's
personal property left in the ecuadorean
embassy post kidnap
then a judge authorized a judicial
request to go through everything it was
an invitation to pillage his privacy and
legal defense last may 20th to 23rd 2019
assange's personal professional legal
and medical effects including cash 27
phones cameras handwritten notebooks sim
and memory cards routers legal documents
digital storage devices laptops and
paper files and binders
the objects were removed by prosecutors
wilson
to anger me i must screw that all up and
fabian chavez in cooperation with a
criminal assistance request by the us
within the extradition process it was a
massive heist for which ecuador was
handsomely rewarded
items were first transferred to quito
and placed under the custody of the
judicial police ecuador allowed the us
to help themselves do assange's
belongings yet he can't access them
i am not sure where his belongings are
now they could be in ecuador where the
u.s examines them or possibly in the u.s
much of it has likely been uploaded to a
secure cloud for remote access in team
forensics by one estimate the computing
and cellular equipment has a 110
terabytes with thousands of encrypted
files
according to the evening standard quote
the search is being carried out under
the authorization of a judge and
following a request for judicial
assistance from the united states
adding that other countries had also
made similar requests if officials do
decide to confiscate any of the
whistleblowers belongings these will be
sent to ecuador for analysis and then
possibly pass on to those seeking
judicial assistance
it has been a year since ecuador sneezed
assange's assets and subsequently gave
access to the united states his arch
adversary
the search and seizure of legal defense
manuscripts cell phones laptops and
memory storage devices is the horror of
every journalist activist researcher or
publisher
assange was robbed
even though his even though it is his
stuff
neither he nor his lawyers family or
colleagues can access it by extension
the assange defense team has been robbed
that is what he meant when he spoke
during an october 21st 2019 case
management hearing
quote
this is not equitable
i can't research anything i can't access
any of my writing it's very difficult
where i am in belmarsh i'm up against a
super power with unlimited resources
i can't think properly
um
and real quick here
this is
we read the
in dc the first time the introduction
for
the book cipher punks which is a
transcript of one of the tv shows that
julian had a series that he did
um but in that first opening and we
actually have a vigil where we went
through the first chapter of that book
in the prologue of it
um he specifically points out how
what it comes down to is that encryption
and the ability to
secure information behind a digital
border
so to speak is
um innate within the universe and it'll
come down to a time
when it essentially is drawn out between
the powers of the state being exercised
to perform torture against julian
and the
ability for them to solve the keys to
these encryption codes and the the words
that he uses is no amount of torture
can solve a math problem or no amount of
force can solve a math problem
and i think that that's what this heist
i hope ultimately shows is that the us
even though they have this immense
physical global power to reach and grab
this man and drag his life down for ten
years
um
still can't cross that barrier of that
encryption wall without him
being the one to allow them to do it
you want to go ahead and move on to the
uh
the contract tracing con i always say
contract
because i feel like these people are
paid pinkertons
oh sorry
i was just gonna say a little lower down
in this article if we could scroll down
a bit in it josh it actually gets into
the possessions like the list of
possessions that they took from julian
so i just wanted to make sure because
that's about the most important thing to
get out to people for all this
well and i think it's also important
just real quick to remember that you
know i mean they
they did all of this for somebody who
supposedly just violated a bail charge
you know
i mean and that's that's a big deal to
remember and now he's you know he is
just on remand even in the eyes of the
law he has not
you know he's not been convicted of
anything
ever so it's again that you know
punishment by
by process and then even making sure
that the process is
not in any way going to be fair to him
whatsoever
that's it i just wanted to get that in
there for this specific article
so uh our own taylor hudak is in my chat
right now on slow news day and she has a
question specifically for you andrew can
andrew explain the definition of
solidarity and what it means to him
so solidarity is
and everyone's laughing this points back
to a super old vigil um but solidarity
is standing alongside someone
um
in so many words it is recognizing that
they have a
struggle as well
and that it may or may not in some way
be interrelated to yours but still
matters
in the grand scale of everyone existing
um i like to add to that and i don't
know if there's a proper word to express
it but
that feeling
of solidarity put into action and i
don't necessarily know what that term is
so if anyone has any suggestions for it
or ideas it's one of those verbal
failings that i have i got a phrase for
it and reverend annie chambers gave it
to me and malcolm x gave it to her and
that phrase is we only get what we
organize and take
i think that defines it pretty well i i
think every little hipster out there in
youtube land should get a nice little
delicate script tattoo of that on them
and then like go flex in the mirror and
be like oh yeah we only get what we
organize and take guess i'll organize
and go take it
at least what we're we're after is a
show of
non-violent force
or solidarity if you will
in washington dc to move a a
conversation into a post-partisan realm
and that conversation is like i was
saying earlier in the vigil no matter
what your cause is it doesn't get a
chance to proliferate if we don't have
free
and open information if we can't
it okay first of all
if we can't have a
unfettered access to what
the truth is through primary source
documentation first person
primary source interviews then all we
have is what we're being told
to think
or how to feel about something by people
whose job it is to obfuscate
so i i can't stress this enough
if your
someone who is currently involved in an
activist cause
on the front of your sign should be your
cause on the back side of your sign
should be
free julian assange and you can feel
free to spin that around as often as you
like because you don't get one without
the other
i think that's so true and to your point
in solidarity it reminds me too of like
even the minds coming together when we
were all in dc you know you had some
different
political
um ideas and different things like that
at least i know for me but um but you
know you see people coming together like
to steve's point and something more
important and so i think that that's
part of what we have to remember
especially in this solidarity movement
is you know you might
hear things depending on what side
you're on that are a little bit you know
that might be like cat claws on a
chalkboard or something but you just you
got to let that go while we concentrate
on
us being able to
you know fight about it with truthful
information later on you know because
right now it's like
we have an alien invasion going on that
we have to stop
i mean i'd like to point out that on
today's vigil just to what you were
talking about we had someone who is in
support of a government ran health care
system
on the same panel
standing in solidarity with someone that
is running an organization that is about
making sure private healthcare still
exists
so in so many words to define the
organization so
ideas like
this like julian assange and press
freedom and basic privacy rights and the
right to trial and things like that are
so much more fundamental that it just
builds this great foundation for
everything else to then be placed upon
true and then also you know the first
amendment you know you don't have any
other civil liberties without that
you have to have that because otherwise
you don't know what's happening with all
the other ones
and you have to you have to have the
second to ensure that you get to keep
the first
and you have to have the fourth so that
you're not freaking
you're what's left of our civil look i i
can't i can't stress enough just how
god-awful it is that that widen
amendment failed by one vote
to make sure that your web browsing
history isn't accessed whenever the hell
the federal government feels like
accessing it to be used against you it's
not that the federal government wants to
send targeted advertising to you so you
buy their shoes
they want to use this information
against you legally against you
politically
to [__] your activism to [__] your
organization
um
i don't really got a whole lot to hide
so
like but i still don't want my browser
history red
and that's a very [__] intimate thing
like right like
your writers not yours
i said that didn't
i think i was talking over it they may
not
so to a point with that too
like as ridiculous as having to argue
against allowing the federal government
unlimited access to your browser history
actually is but for the way that it can
be used beyond just simply targeting
people
is collecting people's data about what
they're observing in a more direct
fashion to be able to tailor the
propaganda better
and i don't know if i'm really
explaining that well or simplifying it
well but essentially being able to see
what content people are viewing
and then
tailoring the content
to make them think a certain way john
bolton has a super pac and if you didn't
know that john bolton has a super pack
john bolton has a super pac and a few
years ago they put out a document
that
basically was an instruction manual for
to do exactly what you're saying how to
best target people to psychologically
manipulate them to get them to vote your
way
there there's a whole workup there's a
white paper on it
um it's one of the things like you'll
have to go find that link but i will
find that link and i'll we can show it
on saturday
yeah
industry built around
um
the regulation of voter thought
essentially
and it starts at its core with the
algorithms that exist within the
um social media companies and the way
they actually allow people's information
to be proliferated
which that was always a big thing that
you know julian assange was talking
about and especially right before they
you know cut his internet at the embassy
that they'd have these advanced
algorithms where you wouldn't even
you would
you know you would have been gone at
step one even though it took you five
steps to get where they wanted you to go
but that you're gonna end up there no
matter what you know and that's that's a
scary thought
i had an absolute legend in uh
independent hip hop on my show this
morning
and i asked him
um like just a general question about i
think i think it was related to julian
assange um but he was like look man
you gotta understand
this isn't
the mid 90s anymore people get big
because they sell out before they make
it big because an algorithm determines
their success
the artist's ability doesn't determine
their success the fans
don't determine their success they don't
know their fans until the algorithm
tells them they need to like it because
it already conforms with everything that
they have co-signed
ma you know with with their consent
fully manufactured and that's just a
wild way to look at it and it's true not
just with art but with information and
with politics like i
i've been able to interview a number of
different candidates for president that
nobody's ever going to get a chance to
vote for because even the green party
and the libertarian party seem to be
doing a pre-selection process
but
those guys
all have the right to be heard their
ideas all have the right to be discussed
but because algorithmically
they get shut out of the conversation
before
a real conversation takes place
they're you know
confined to the the dark corners of the
interwebs
well and you have you know this
convincing of the public going on that
it's you know it's not in your interest
to hear these these other stupid
candidates you know that's always been a
complaint i've had even with the
presidential debates that we don't have
a third party in there you know i mean
that's even if you say that that you
know that's nothing for the people okay
well then let them make that let's let
us make that decision
you know and i understand there has to
be some process where you can't have you
know like i can't just be on the
presidential debate because i decide to
you know but still you see what i'm
saying
and
so julian had talked about the use of
artificial intelligence propaganda i
think that was one of the last
conversations he got to have before he
got
um cut from
[Music]
actually being able to speak and
communicate
and so i just want to point out to
people because fee did a really good job
of breaking down
the way money and our current media
structure influences the way people
consume content
and
i just like to leave people with the
idea of being aware that there are some
people and channels and
media institutions
that exist specifically to herd people
into specific narratives and it applies
broadly and sometimes it's individuals
and sometimes it is institutions but
um
just keep an eye out for those um
because it's one of those things that
you can't really tear it down but at the
same time you have to be intimately
aware of when something like that is
occurring
and sometimes it's individual
institutions and sometimes it's
individuals who should be
institutionalized that work for the
institutions who are individually doing
what andrew just said
you're welcome
but so do we want to talk about privacy
international
uh yeah let's do that because it it
really is one of those things where
where
i feel like the concept of contact
tracing
the
the snitch patrols
they're never going away there's going
to be
multiple reasons to deploy a snitch army
throughout especially as we become more
and more impossibly authoritarian so
yeah let's go ahead and and take a look
at that one
i had it up
where'd it go
so it starts by going over
um it's what they call key findings and
privacy international has done great
work they speak out against a whole lot
of things
but this in particular i want to point
out because it's something that's very
disconcerting to me as someone that
understands why privacy exists which is
to limit people's ability to
um
bring down
institutions against other individuals
essentially not allowing people to use
processes punishment
and this contact tracing throughout this
entire article
is framed as well we can do it the right
way
and i think that the entire framing of
this article
is
completely
i don't know just overshadowed by the
fact that they're not arguing against
contact tracing they're just arguing
against how to make it okay
well i think that goes to the point of
the you know the echo chamber which are
you know allowed a certain lively debate
within that but what's not on the table
is whether contract tracing is okay in
the first place
i can't get this stupid article to load
so i'm
useless right now i'm floundering
closing out every other do you want to
lead on this weekend
okay
well if anybody has it up already go
ahead and
run with it
is there any specific part in here
andrew that you kind of wanted to go
over
like highlight the key findings of the
privacy international article
okay
um so their key findings guys are
contact tracing is an important
emergency healthcare initiative and is
necessarily invasive
coronavirus apps do much more and much
less than manual contact tracing
there are dangerous tracing initiatives
that regular regularly report on your
activities there are interesting
initiatives that may or may not work
these are somewhat privacy aware and can
be either centralized or decentralized
apple and google support decentralized
proximity tracing and privacy and
security aware ways
uh those who build these systems need to
quickly build and engender trust they've
been f flailing in secrecy
now that's
that's interesting wording
especially when it comes to apple and
google apple and google support
decentralized proximity tracing in
privacy and security aware ways
that is the exact same thing as
a politician supporting
medicare for all look at pramila j pal
for example who wrote a medicare for all
bill introduced it into congress last
year ostensibly supports
medicare parole
just the other day hopped on the
tweeters and said americans need access
to affordable health care
which is the exact same thing is saying
[__] you peasant you're not getting your
medicare for all you're not getting
universal health care you're not you're
not we're going to work on getting you
access to affordable health care i
have access to a bugatti
i cannot afford
a bugatti but i have access to it
you know the in the same way that google
and apple support
the privacy and security awareness in a
decentralized fashion but
will they implement it
hell no
they're already not
well and one thing too i was going to
ask you guys maybe you could confirm
this but i know that i had heard that i
thought that they were just kind of
automatically loading this into the
updates anyhow
is that correct or it's not just they're
talking about doing that no that's in
your may update
the the contact tracing app is in your
may update and i think it's important we
should try to get sean back on
um as soon as possible just to give
people
some type of presentation about
installing um like f droid or something
on an iphone or things like that just so
that way it can
i don't get around it i don't know if
we're allowed to show people how to do
something like that but i feel like we
should
and i think sean could probably put
something together pretty quick to help
us out i feel like if it'll get a for a
in trouble then we can do it through
slow news day and all get in trouble
wait yeah i really you know i mean
i'll go ahead and step up for that one
but i will
but i want to appointment
in this privacy international article
there's not one mention of volunteer
right they mentioned the uk multiple
times they talk about their system and
how they're
rolling out contact tracing apps and
things like that but not once do they
mention the
actual private intelligence company that
is running
the data sets for this and the people
and other organizations and institutions
that have contracts with that company
that would then be able to access those
data sets and i think that that's
highly irresponsible to not mention
anything about volunteer to not mention
anything about the five eyes
and for a
international privacy institution to not
put five eyes and pollen here on the
front of this coronavirus contact racing
is
beyond irresponsible to put it
to put it lightly
who have you heard reference the five
eyes outside of like people who are like
personal friends with susie dawson
i mean the honest that's an honest
question like is there a discussion
about the five eyes global intelligence
sharing network going on in another
corner of the internet that i'm unaware
of because like the first time that i
heard it julian had brought it up
it was a like a 2012 speech maybe um he
was already in the embassy it was
i mean he was giving like a
speech at a conference or something like
that and he mentioned it and i was like
what the [__] is
huh
and it's one of those things where like
if you know great but like we did it's
not a secret handshake more people
should know
what
this institution is and who they are and
what they do and volunteer is involved
in the three different pieces of
healthcare legislation in australia
right now too
like
that will give them control of three of
the five five eyes nations and there's
no alarms being sounded at any level of
the media about that level of
consolidation of information that i'm
aware of
no and every single one of those
simulated exercises from dark winter all
the way on to event 201 crimson
contagion all of them all of them what's
baked into it continuity of government
and
a complete shutdown of the people's
internet
who prospers during that transitional
continuity of government period it's
organizations like palantir who not only
have the contracts but they have
all of our data
they have all of our information and
they've got direct
um
clients they they've got direct clients
who
sole purpose of their job is to target
activists organizers and and people who
are trying to
take an individual or collective stand
for
some level of corporate responsibility
and because we got to be we're going to
start wrapping up here in a little bit
we got a a couple minutes but just to
kind of piggyback off of something that
steve had been talking about
um
the the entire
coronavirus institution now essentially
that's forming that's allowing
all of this crazy stuff to happen um a
lot of times you hear the argument from
people
um when you try to talk to them about
like the global power consolidation
that's happening right now with all of
these institutions
and they say well they're they're not
just going to go bankrupt like they're
not just going to close down all this
and shut it down for nothing
um and
a lot of times
that they will because it's an
investment into a larger a larger plan
the big players were still allowed to
continue and keep operating throughout
all this the small businesses were
destroyed
but
those larger institutions took a loss
because there's a lot to gain down the
road and there's a lot of money to be
made through the use of
intelligence community databasing
contact tracing and advertising
not including the political torture that
can come from it by selling this
information off
um
but
i would like to thank everybody for
joining us tonight for our 46th vigil um
we will be back again on saturday at 1
pm eastern time
my name is andrew smith you can find me
on twitter at andrew zigman
z-i-g-m-u-n-d
and you can find all of us and this on
twitter at action underscore the number
four assange and action for assange on
youtube as well
and hi everybody into the chat and thank
you to josh and kimber as well and uh my
name is kendra christian and you can
find me on twitter at edubs13 and you
can follow denver free assange at dnv
freeja
if you're seeing me for the first time
my name's steve boikenan i do host a
show called slow news day you can find
it here on youtube by typing slow
newsday podcast into your search bar i
am also on the rockfin d live and a
couple other platforms occasionally
depending on how much they are covering
me at the moment um
do check out the interview i did with ra
the rugged man this morning it's
freaking it's a really good conversation
ray mcgovern will be on my show this
sunday i'm really looking forward to
that um i don't have a lot book this
week
i'm gonna be on a panel with nico house
on thursday um
our wonderful tech guy here sleepy josh
is also my tech guy and i'm trying not
to kill him because i tried to the last
few weeks um
so i'm taking a break from murdering my
tech guys slowly uh and uh
and just trying to get out some quality
shows in between um big thanks to our
guests tonight uh fiorella isabel john
kiriakou and norman singleton um again
thanks sleepy josh on the ones and twos
mean panda for the graphics um you guys
in the chat we we love you we we do uh
we we do this
uh because
you guys give us
all of the energy in the world for us
thank you very very much um
do pass around the gofundme link do look
at uh the action link for the week um if
you can donate to the gofundme please do
that if you can't again no big deal just
proliferate the link